<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Journals on Intellectual Web</title>
    <link>https://stg.words.yudocaa.in/journal/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Journals on Intellectual Web</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 26 Mar 2019 18:30:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://stg.words.yudocaa.in/journal/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Kubernetes Day India 2019, Bangalore</title>
      <link>https://stg.words.yudocaa.in/journal/kubernetes-day-india-2019-bangalore/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Mar 2019 18:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://stg.words.yudocaa.in/journal/kubernetes-day-india-2019-bangalore/</guid>
      <description>I returned to another conference with the jetlag of another conference, FOSSASIA but this conference was something I was very eagerly waiting to attend. Why? Well there are a couple of reasons, but the main reason for which I bought the ticket was to listen to Liz Rice in person.
The other reason was to see and meet the growing community of Kubernetes in Bangalore.
23rd March 2019, I woke up early morning and left along with Sayani, and Saptak to this place quite outside of Bangalore.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>FOSSASIA 2019</title>
      <link>https://stg.words.yudocaa.in/journal/fossasia-2019/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Mar 2019 18:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://stg.words.yudocaa.in/journal/fossasia-2019/</guid>
      <description>I was back to FOSSASIA this year after a gap of an year and nothing had changed other than the venue. The event had the same level of enthusiasm as before, though the crowd seemed to be less compared to the previous years.
This FOSSASIA was more special for the participants, organizers and the volunteers because this was the 10th year of the event. Kudos, to the organizing team for doing it successfully for last 10 years!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fedora 29 Bangalore Release Party</title>
      <link>https://stg.words.yudocaa.in/journal/fedora-29-bangalore-release-party/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Nov 2018 18:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://stg.words.yudocaa.in/journal/fedora-29-bangalore-release-party/</guid>
      <description>23rd November 2018
The Fedora community of Bangalore assembled at the Red Hat Bangalore office. The event was scheduled to start at 1300, but the lunch at the office postponed the event by 45 mins.
Sumantro kicked off the event with a small introduction, following which Vipul gave an introduction of open source with a short choco-chip story.
Sumantro back on stage after that talking about the &amp;ldquo;What&amp;rsquo;s coming next?&amp;rdquo;, from discussing about GNOME/Pantheon, to Python 2 deprecation, to Ansible, to IoT, to Modularity.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introducing SkipTheLine</title>
      <link>https://stg.words.yudocaa.in/journal/introducing-skiptheline/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Oct 2018 18:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://stg.words.yudocaa.in/journal/introducing-skiptheline/</guid>
      <description>2013 The year I graduated from a third-tier college in Durgapur. I did not expect much from the college, mostly because of the poor placement record in the college.
To get myself a job, I was primarily going through hasjob.co and any job opportunities that came through Bangpypers mailing list.
Finally, I landed myself into an internship and later which turned into a full-time at HackerEarth was through the hasjob.co.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PyLadies Pune Meetup - February 2017</title>
      <link>https://stg.words.yudocaa.in/journal/pyladies-pune-meetup-feb-2017/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Feb 2017 20:30:00 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://stg.words.yudocaa.in/journal/pyladies-pune-meetup-feb-2017/</guid>
      <description>The PyLadies Pune February Meetup was held on 6th Feb at reserved-bit. Kushal took a session on MicroPython on the MicroBit boards. Thanks to @ntoll for sending over the MicroBits for workshops.
I reached down to the venue a bit late. On reaching the venue, Kushal told me that he forgot the boards at home and I went to his place to pick the MicroBits.
  Most of the participants were regular participants for the meetup so Kushal took a quick course on Python.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Vote for me in Trek Photographer of the month</title>
      <link>https://stg.words.yudocaa.in/journal/trek-photographer-dec-2016/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Jan 2017 11:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://stg.words.yudocaa.in/journal/trek-photographer-dec-2016/</guid>
      <description>I have been nominated for the Trek Photographer of the Month. I am grateful to the judges for nominating me. Appreciate if you vote for me. I&amp;rsquo;m up against some really tough competition :)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PyCon India 2016</title>
      <link>https://stg.words.yudocaa.in/journal/pycon-india-2016/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 Nov 2016 15:10:00 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://stg.words.yudocaa.in/journal/pycon-india-2016/</guid>
      <description>PyCon India, this year was held at New Delhi at the JNU Convention Center.
Dev Sprints During the Dev Sprint, Farhaan and Vivek were sprinting on Fedora Infrastructure projects primarily helping people contribute to Pagure.
Other projects/orgs like SciPy, Red Hat team, FOSSAsia, Junction etc were also sprinting.
The Dev Sprint turned out to have a good participation and couple of PRs were sent out by the participations. More than that, it’s more about participants getting to know about on how to contribute.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fedora Meetup Pune August 2016</title>
      <link>https://stg.words.yudocaa.in/journal/fedora-meetup-august-2016/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Aug 2016 21:52:00 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://stg.words.yudocaa.in/journal/fedora-meetup-august-2016/</guid>
      <description>Fedora Pune Meetup for the month of August 2016 happened today at our usual location. We had in total 12 people turning out for the meetup.
The event started with introductions and we had two new comers joining us this time, Trishna and Prathamesh.
This time the event was mostly foccused around re-writing the GNU C Library Manual using reStructuredText and Sphinx. This task was decided during the release event that we had last month.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Flock 2016</title>
      <link>https://stg.words.yudocaa.in/journal/flock-2016/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Aug 2016 16:30:00 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://stg.words.yudocaa.in/journal/flock-2016/</guid>
      <description>Flock 2016 was held in the beautiful city of Krakow, Poland from August 2nd - August 5th, 2016.
Day -1 Reached Krakow tired. Spent most of the time sleeping.
Day 0 A lot of attendees started coming in. Met with a lot of people IRL whom I generally talked over on IRC. In the afternoon, we went out for the city tour. Visiting the Oskar Schindler’s Enamel Factory was a place I always wanted to visit ever since I watched the movie Schindler’s List.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fedora 24 Release event</title>
      <link>https://stg.words.yudocaa.in/journal/fedora-24-release-event/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Jul 2016 14:09:43 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://stg.words.yudocaa.in/journal/fedora-24-release-event/</guid>
      <description>On 9th July 2016, we had our Fedora 24 release party in Pune. The release party took place at my place. We saw a lot of familiar faces from our regular Fedora Meetup.
Chandan Kumar started the event with explaining the new features in Fedora 24. People discussed on how things has changed in Fedora 24. Parag and Siddhesh talked on how it&amp;rsquo;s important to learn things and people chipped in with their ideas.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>FOSSASIA 2016 - Day 2</title>
      <link>https://stg.words.yudocaa.in/journal/fossasia-2016-day-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Mar 2016 17:22:00 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://stg.words.yudocaa.in/journal/fossasia-2016-day-2/</guid>
      <description>I left early for the venue as haseeb had the first talk of the day and I was volunteering for the Python track.
The day started off with a talk by Stephanie Taylor on Introduction to GSoC, and GCI. She talked about the programs Google Summer of Code and Google Code In. She shared some statistics from the past years. The students of GCI last year completed more than 4k tasks, among them 1k+ was done by the students under FOSSASIA organization.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>FOSSASIA 2016 - Day 1</title>
      <link>https://stg.words.yudocaa.in/journal/fossasia-2016-day-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Mar 2016 17:01:00 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://stg.words.yudocaa.in/journal/fossasia-2016-day-1/</guid>
      <description>FOSSASIA 2016, Asia&amp;rsquo;s premier conference on Free and Open Software was held at Science Center, Singapore.
I arrived Singapore 18th morning, the same day the event was starting. Due to track issues, the metro was running late and I reached the venue around 1100 local time. I directly went to the auditorium where the event was happening. I had already missed the morning talks. It was Tea break when I reached.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fedimg: Course of Action</title>
      <link>https://stg.words.yudocaa.in/journal/fedimg-course-of-action/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 23 Jan 2016 11:48:00 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://stg.words.yudocaa.in/journal/fedimg-course-of-action/</guid>
      <description>Fedimg is a Python-powered service which is built to make Fedora-Cloud images available on popular cloud providers, such as Amazon Web Services (AWS). The plans are to support more cloud providers such as Rackspace, Google Compute Engine.
Fedimg listens for the messages from Fedmsg for the Koji image builds.
Plan of work
  Add scripts to remove old AMIs we have uploaded (https://github.com/fedora-infra/fedimg/issues/37)
Storing the AMIs are costing us lot.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fedora Meetup Pune - January 2016</title>
      <link>https://stg.words.yudocaa.in/journal/fedora-meetup-pune-january-2016/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Jan 2016 20:28:43 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://stg.words.yudocaa.in/journal/fedora-meetup-pune-january-2016/</guid>
      <description>On 15th January 2016, we had our first Fedora meetup at Pune. The venue was earlier decided to be Red Hat office, Pune but due to unavailability of space the meetup was moved to my apartment.
The meetup was scheduled to start around 14:30 IST but with people pouring in a bit late, we started the event at 15:00 IST. The turnout was good and much more than what we had expected with a total of 18 people turning out.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Four Weeks in Fedora</title>
      <link>https://stg.words.yudocaa.in/journal/four-weeks-in-fedora/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Nov 2015 08:24:43 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://stg.words.yudocaa.in/journal/four-weeks-in-fedora/</guid>
      <description>26th of October 2015, I joined Red Hat as a part of the Fedora Engineering Team.
I have been contributing to the Fedora for couple of years now starting from the contributing to askbot-devel while we were gearing up for the Ask Fedora release. This year in July, I along with kushal, rtnpro, praveenkumar started working on Autocloud, as a part of the Two-Week Atomic during the Fedora 23 cycle. So, I last couple of years of I have met and worked with a lot of people in the Fedora community.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Leaving HackerEarth</title>
      <link>https://stg.words.yudocaa.in/journal/leaving-hackerearth/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Oct 2015 08:24:43 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://stg.words.yudocaa.in/journal/leaving-hackerearth/</guid>
      <description>It&amp;rsquo;s very hard to write but I am leaving HackerEarth.
2013 and internship My college days were coming to an end with placements all around. I was sure to join in a startup. One fine day, I saw a job posting on hasjob on 12th December 2012 that boldly said &amp;ldquo;HackerEarth is buidling its initial team - Python/Django enthusiast needed&amp;rdquo;. The idea made me apply to HackerEarth and after a few rounds of email with Sachin and Vivek.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fedora Meetup 2015</title>
      <link>https://stg.words.yudocaa.in/journal/fedora-meetup-2015/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Jul 2015 22:48:00 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://stg.words.yudocaa.in/journal/fedora-meetup-2015/</guid>
      <description>Fedora July Meetup 2015 happened at Hasgeek office, Indiranagar on July 04, 2015 at 06:30 PM.
Attendees:
 Sayan Chowdhury Ratnadeep Debnath Lalatendu Mohanty Nitish Bharadwaj Devyani Kota Praseetha KR Sharat MR  Topics discussed:
 Introduction to Fedora and what&amp;rsquo;s new in Fedora 22 Reproduce Bugs on Vagrant(libvrt) and identify missing features Introduction to RPM Packaging Fedora Hubs  It&amp;rsquo;s good to know more and more people are turning up for the meetup.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>FUDCon India 2015</title>
      <link>https://stg.words.yudocaa.in/journal/fudcon-india-2015/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Jul 2015 16:29:00 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://stg.words.yudocaa.in/journal/fudcon-india-2015/</guid>
      <description>I spent the last weekend of June at FUDCon India. FUDCon is the Fedora Users and Developers Conference organized in different parts of the world. The last FUDCon APAC that happened in India was in 2011 which i could not attend because of my college. Being a Fedora user for 6 years now I always wanted to attend one FUDCon. FUDCon APAC this year was held at MIT College of Enginnering Pune.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fedora 21 Release Party, Bangalore</title>
      <link>https://stg.words.yudocaa.in/journal/fedora-21-release-party-bangalore/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Jan 2015 12:00:00 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://stg.words.yudocaa.in/journal/fedora-21-release-party-bangalore/</guid>
      <description>The Fedora Project announced the release of Fedora 21 on December 09, 2014. To celebrate the release a [Fedora 21 release party] (https://fedoraproject.org/wiki/Release_Party_F21_Bangalore) was organized at Red Hat, Bangalore with the help of Archit and Humble.
The event was scheduled to start at 10AM but people started coming in from 9:30AM itself. Around 40 people turned up among them a good number were college students.
The release party finally started at 10:30AM by [Archit] (https://fedoraproject.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bangalore Fedora Meetup, 8th March 2014</title>
      <link>https://stg.words.yudocaa.in/journal/bangalore-fedora-meetup-8th-march-2014/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 08 Mar 2014 22:18:06 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://stg.words.yudocaa.in/journal/bangalore-fedora-meetup-8th-march-2014/</guid>
      <description>After a long time, we had a Bangalore Fedora meetup(March 8, 2014) at Red Hat, Bangalore.
The attendees for the event were:
 Anil Shah Varun Shastry Rejy M Cyriac Ratnadeep Debnath Sayan Chowdhury Sarup Banskota  The discussion took place around the following agendas:
Fedora Monthly Meetup We decided start off with a local Fedora meetup here in Bangalore every month to chalk out on how to reach to a greater audience in and around city to evangelize on Fedora, FOSS and contributing back to the community.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Waartaa applies GSoC 2014</title>
      <link>https://stg.words.yudocaa.in/journal/waartaa-applies-gsoc-2014/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Mar 2014 07:20:23 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://stg.words.yudocaa.in/journal/waartaa-applies-gsoc-2014/</guid>
      <description>We are elated to inform you that Waartaa has been accepted as a project idea for GSoC under Fedora&amp;rsquo;s umbrella.
For those who are new to Waartaa, Waartaa is an open-source communication tool for teams and groups. It is built on top of IRC. Currently, Waartaa is an IRC client as a service and it supports centralized logging, 24x7 idling, notifications and unique identity to a user on IRC. The source code is available at https://github.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mukti 2014</title>
      <link>https://stg.words.yudocaa.in/journal/mukti-2014/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Mar 2014 01:45:03 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://stg.words.yudocaa.in/journal/mukti-2014/</guid>
      <description>Mukti 2014 is the annual national level technical symposium on Free and Open Source Software of the GNU/Linux Users’ Group NIT Durgapur held from 31st January - 2nd February 2014.
I&amp;rsquo;ve been attending Mukti for last four years. Unlike, the previous years when i usually attended Mukti as a student participant, this year I attended Mukti as a guest speaker.
Day 0 (30th January 2014) After a hectic travel from Bangalore to Durgapur via Kolkata.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>An open letter to Bloggers from Kolkata.</title>
      <link>https://stg.words.yudocaa.in/journal/an-open-letter-to-bloggers-from-kolkata/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Mar 2014 00:31:43 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://stg.words.yudocaa.in/journal/an-open-letter-to-bloggers-from-kolkata/</guid>
      <description>On February 23, 2014 at 4:43pm, Anirban Saha made a post on Facebook
Where are the Kolkata Bloggers? Like, seriously ?
In August 8, 2009, Webreps organised Kolkata Bloggers Meet. That time I joined Webreps. In October 31, 2009, we organised the BCET Bloggers workshop in BCET. There BCREC and NITDgp also joined in. Have been active ever since then.
In 2014 - I hardly find any blogger visible and audible.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mozilla Summit 2013</title>
      <link>https://stg.words.yudocaa.in/journal/mozilla-summit-2013/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Nov 2013 12:00:00 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://stg.words.yudocaa.in/journal/mozilla-summit-2013/</guid>
      <description>I could not sleep the night i got the invitation mail from Mozilla to attend Mozilla Summit 2013. I was roaming around my college hostel waking up everybody from their sleep just to tell them that “I have been invited to Mozilla Summit 2013 at Santa Clara, CA”. I was really very excited as this was be my first international travel.
Finally the month of October came. rtnpro and I left for bangalore airport early (all due to exitement).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PyCon India 2013</title>
      <link>https://stg.words.yudocaa.in/journal/pycon-india-2013/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Sep 2013 12:00:00 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://stg.words.yudocaa.in/journal/pycon-india-2013/</guid>
      <description>Python Month I attended last year’s PyCon India, while in college and it was a great experience. After shifting to Bangalore this year, I thought why not volunteer Pycon India this year.
I was a regular attendee to the Pycon India meetings held at the Goibibo office at M.G.Road. This year it was thought to celebrate the month of August Python Month as a part of PyCon this year. As a part of Python Month, volunteers would go to various college across the country to evangelize and teach python to college students.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Never Do it for Free</title>
      <link>https://stg.words.yudocaa.in/journal/never-do-it-for-free/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 08 Jun 2013 12:00:00 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://stg.words.yudocaa.in/journal/never-do-it-for-free/</guid>
      <description>This was legendary quote given by “The Joker” in the movie The Dark Knight.
I was never a fan of this quote, until, I realized “The Joker” parted the right message, not for all cases but Yes this quote does hold true for certain instances.
Choose your students wisely. :P</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>dgplug Summer Training 2013</title>
      <link>https://stg.words.yudocaa.in/journal/dgplug-summer-training-2013/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Apr 2013 12:00:00 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://stg.words.yudocaa.in/journal/dgplug-summer-training-2013/</guid>
      <description>The time has come again this year for the dgplug summer training.
The summer training is conducted each year during the month of June. Though, we cannot call June as the summer season but end of June is a suitable time for most of the Indian students. During this summer training, a number of upstream developers give talk on various open-source technologies. This guides the student on how to contribute back to open source.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
