<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>gsoc on Intellectual Web</title>
    <link>https://words.yudocaa.in/tags/gsoc/</link>
    <description>Recent content in gsoc on Intellectual Web</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 07 Mar 2014 07:20:23 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://words.yudocaa.in/tags/gsoc/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Waartaa applies GSoC 2014</title>
      <link>https://words.yudocaa.in/journal/waartaa-applies-gsoc-2014/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Mar 2014 07:20:23 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://words.yudocaa.in/journal/waartaa-applies-gsoc-2014/</guid>
      <description>We are elated to inform you that Waartaa has been accepted as a project idea for GSoC under Fedora&amp;rsquo;s umbrella.
For those who are new to Waartaa, Waartaa is an open-source communication tool for teams and groups. It is built on top of IRC. Currently, Waartaa is an IRC client as a service and it supports centralized logging, 24x7 idling, notifications and unique identity to a user on IRC. The source code is available at https://github.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Darkserver Improvement: Pen Down</title>
      <link>https://words.yudocaa.in/blog/darkserver-improvement-pen-down/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Sep 2013 12:00:00 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://words.yudocaa.in/blog/darkserver-improvement-pen-down/</guid>
      <description>Lot of things to do!
Lot of things to do!
Lot of things to do!
This was continuously revovlving around my head for last 2 weeks. I had to deploy the work i had done on staging instance and test it. But wait! I had never written a setup.py before, never made a RPM package before.
While in college, I had a fascination toward RPM packaging as most of my college seniors had created a RPM package sometime or other.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Darkserver Improvement: Web Dashboard</title>
      <link>https://words.yudocaa.in/blog/darkserver-improvement-web-dashboard/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Sep 2013 12:00:00 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://words.yudocaa.in/blog/darkserver-improvement-web-dashboard/</guid>
      <description>There has been a lot of changes since I last posted my blog.
Darkserver’s command line dashboard now supports the secondary architecture. You can easily shutdown the darkproducer of specifying which architecture to shutdown.
.. code::
dark&amp;gt; shutdown darkproducer arch  The support for multiple buildqueues was removed.
After a rigorous testing on my laptop, i pushed the code to the dev instance that was assigned to me. But, a mysterious error happened, nor the pid or the daemon of darkproducer was getting created.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Darkserver Improvement</title>
      <link>https://words.yudocaa.in/blog/darkserver-improvement/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Jul 2013 12:00:00 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://words.yudocaa.in/blog/darkserver-improvement/</guid>
      <description>I am currently doing some manual testing of my code, and it proved to be vital. It helped me figure out a lot of bugs. One of seemed weird to me in the beginning: The get here returned an error.
.. code::
Method Not Allowed This is an XML-RPC server. Only POST requests are accepted.  The project required a heavy amount of download, so my mentor gave me a dev instance to test out my code, all seemed to be fine, with the code properly working on local machine.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Darkserver Improvement: Week Two and Week Three</title>
      <link>https://words.yudocaa.in/blog/darkserver-improvement-week-two-and-week-three/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Jul 2013 12:00:00 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://words.yudocaa.in/blog/darkserver-improvement-week-two-and-week-three/</guid>
      <description>It’s been two weeks since i last posted my report on Darkserver. I could not post week two update as I had been down with bad health(seasonal changes + Loo). With the week coming to an end and /me recovering from fever, i badly hurt my right wrist and that was end of it. I somehow manage to move myself to a new city, Bengaluru. The week passed as a trauma for me :’(</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Google Summer of Code 2013: Welcome Kit</title>
      <link>https://words.yudocaa.in/blog/google-summer-of-code-2013-welcome-kit/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Jun 2013 12:00:00 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://words.yudocaa.in/blog/google-summer-of-code-2013-welcome-kit/</guid>
      <description>Today, I got my GSoC welcome Kit. YaY!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Darkserver Improvement: Week One</title>
      <link>https://words.yudocaa.in/blog/darkserver-improvement-week-one/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Jun 2013 12:00:00 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://words.yudocaa.in/blog/darkserver-improvement-week-one/</guid>
      <description>The ‘Google Summer of Code’ code period began on June 17 and it’s already one week into it. Prior to the beginning of the coding period, I went into the depths of the darkserver codebase. In the current version of Darkserver, the link present in the libimporter are hardlinks and it is pretty well visible on Github
So, I removed the urls and the values from the libimporter and made it configurable via config files.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Darkserver Improvement: Random Scribblings</title>
      <link>https://words.yudocaa.in/blog/darkserver-improvement-random-scribblings/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Jun 2013 12:00:00 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://words.yudocaa.in/blog/darkserver-improvement-random-scribblings/</guid>
      <description>It was worth trying to sit down with pen and paper and sketch out the compete workflow of Darkserver. I got the idea to try out this stuff from Vivek’s blogpost. Though, I could not get hold of a board but A4 did the job for me and it is really proving out to be helpful.
.. slides: ../galleries/random_scribblings.JPG ../galleries/random_scribblings2.JPG</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Darkserver Improvement: Getting Prepared</title>
      <link>https://words.yudocaa.in/blog/darkserver-improvement-getting-prepared/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 22 Jun 2013 12:00:00 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://words.yudocaa.in/blog/darkserver-improvement-getting-prepared/</guid>
      <description>The Google Summer of Code 2013 results was declared on 27th May 2013, in between my semester exam so i had no time to devote until the end of my semester exams and /me returning back to my home.
With the beginning of the 2nd week of June, I started to hack around with the project, Darkserver. The project is available on GitHub.
That week was pretty much a reading week rather than coding week as I had to go through all kinds of documentation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Darkserver Improvement: Google Summer of Code 2013</title>
      <link>https://words.yudocaa.in/blog/darkserver-improvement-google-summer-of-code-2013/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Jun 2013 12:00:00 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://words.yudocaa.in/blog/darkserver-improvement-google-summer-of-code-2013/</guid>
      <description>.. image:: ../galleries/gsoc.jpg :align: center
It’s better later than never. It’s been two week since the Google Summer of Code 2013 results were announced and I am glad to say that I got selected this year.
I will be working on Darkserver Improvement under Fedora. One can see a draft of my proposal here. My mentor is Kushal Das and i am really helpful for helping me out in the whole process both in code and application.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
