<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Blogs on Intellectual Web</title>
    <link>https://stg.words.yudocaa.in/blog/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Blogs on Intellectual Web</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 21 Feb 2021 18:30:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://stg.words.yudocaa.in/blog/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Love Boredom</title>
      <link>https://stg.words.yudocaa.in/blog/love-boredom/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Feb 2021 18:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://stg.words.yudocaa.in/blog/love-boredom/</guid>
      <description>I was talking to Jason today, discussing aspects of life and building habits.
Last week was pretty rough, devoid of motivation to maintain my habits. To which he said to me, &amp;ldquo;to fall in love with boredom&amp;rdquo; and passed me a couple of blog post from James Clear.
 How to Fall in Love With Boredom and Unlock Your Mental Toughness How to Stay Focused When You Get Bored Working Toward Your Goals Lessons on Success and Deliberate Practice from Mozart, Picasso, and Kobe Bryant  The first blog was one I could relate to in an instant.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>git config</title>
      <link>https://stg.words.yudocaa.in/blog/git-config/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 May 2020 18:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://stg.words.yudocaa.in/blog/git-config/</guid>
      <description>Git comes with this handy tool that let&amp;rsquo;s you manage your Git configuration with ease.
Configuration Levels   --local
(Default) Local configuration values are stored and managed at the repository level. The values are stored in a file found in the repo&amp;rsquo;s .git directory: .git/config
If you are planning to set some configuration only to be used by the specific repo you are in, then go ahead with using --local.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Force git to use git:// instead of https://</title>
      <link>https://stg.words.yudocaa.in/blog/force-git-to-use-git-instead-of-https/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Jul 2019 18:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://stg.words.yudocaa.in/blog/force-git-to-use-git-instead-of-https/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;m an advocate of using SSH authentication and connecting to services like Github, Gitlab, and many others. I do make sure that the use the git:// URL while cloning the repo but sometimes I do make mistake of using the https:// instead. Only to later realise when git prompts me to enter my username to authenticate the SSH connection. This is when I have to manually reset my git remote URL.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Editing Git commits from history</title>
      <link>https://stg.words.yudocaa.in/blog/editing-git-commits-from-history/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Feb 2019 18:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://stg.words.yudocaa.in/blog/editing-git-commits-from-history/</guid>
      <description>Let&amp;rsquo;s say you&amp;rsquo;ve raised a Pull Request on GitHub with 3 commits as shown below.
d46d2f8a (HEAD -&amp;gt; feature, devel/feature) Add Fedora system to handle the Fedora Cloud images f726b033 vendor: Add new dep github.com/ulikunitz/xz dbdbda67 Split release and pre-release to handle multiple systems Here, d46d2f8a is the HEAD, followed by f726b033 and dbdbda67.
Your reviewers go through the commits, and suggest changes to some files. The suggestions now need to be applied to the commit dbdbda67.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Vim, Wish I knew this about you before!</title>
      <link>https://stg.words.yudocaa.in/blog/vim-wish-i-knew-this-about-you-before/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Jan 2019 18:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://stg.words.yudocaa.in/blog/vim-wish-i-knew-this-about-you-before/</guid>
      <description>Almost all my life since I have started working around open source projects I have been a Vim user. That does not mean that I did not look into other options. I&amp;rsquo;ve tried my hands on Emacs, Sublime Text, Visual Studio Code, Atom, et cetera. But, none of them pleased me like vim.
2018, I started working on Golang, and vim had to adapt to my needs, but it did not quite succeed and I made my switch to neovim around the end of the year.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fedora AMIs for Arm-Based EC2 Instances (A1)</title>
      <link>https://stg.words.yudocaa.in/blog/fedora-amis-for-ec2-instances-a1-powered-by-arm-based-aws-graviton-processors/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Nov 2018 18:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://stg.words.yudocaa.in/blog/fedora-amis-for-ec2-instances-a1-powered-by-arm-based-aws-graviton-processors/</guid>
      <description>AWS recently announced their new fleet of A1 EC2 instances which is powered by ARM at AWS re:Invent.
Gladly, the Fedora Kernel Team (Laura Abbott, Justin Forbes and Jeremy Cline) and Peter Robinson had already everything in place. The only missing piece was to add the support to fedimg to create arm64 based AMIs.
With the release of fedimg==2.4.0 (thanks to Patrick), the new AMIs were happily getting uploaded to AWS and with a slight delay, Fedora had the support for the arm64 along with the x86_64 AMIs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fedora AMIs gets ENA support</title>
      <link>https://stg.words.yudocaa.in/blog/fedora-amis-gets-ena-support/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 May 2018 18:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://stg.words.yudocaa.in/blog/fedora-amis-gets-ena-support/</guid>
      <description>It’s been a while that Amazon introduced Elastic Network Adapter (ENA) Support to their cloud. Amazon EC2 provides enhanced networking capabilities to C5, C5 with instance storage, F1, G3, H1, I3, m4.16xlarge, M5, P2, P3, R4, and X1 instances through the Elastic Network Adapter (ENA).
With the Fedora 28 release, the Fedora AMIs come with the ENA support.
To check whether an AMI has the Enhanced Networking with ENA-Enabled, you can query the AWS EC2 API, using the AWS Command Line Interface.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Redesigning fedimg (Part 2): Communication with AWS</title>
      <link>https://stg.words.yudocaa.in/blog/redesigning-fedimg-part-ii/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Feb 2017 12:00:00 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://stg.words.yudocaa.in/blog/redesigning-fedimg-part-ii/</guid>
      <description>In the previous post, I discussed what is fedimg and how it works currently. In this post, I plan to explain the issue in the current uploading process of the AMIs and how we plan to fix it.
What&amp;rsquo;s the problem? fedimg boots an utility instance using the RHEL AMI configured for that region.
The problem with this design is that while adding a new region we need to look for the appropriate RHEL AMI in the newer region first.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Basic Soldering Workshop at reserved-bit</title>
      <link>https://stg.words.yudocaa.in/blog/soldering-workshop-at-rb/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Feb 2017 15:00:00 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://stg.words.yudocaa.in/blog/soldering-workshop-at-rb/</guid>
      <description>This weekend there will be a soldering workshop conducted at reserved-bit. The workshop is on 5th Feb 2017 from 10:00 - 13:00.
The 3-hour workshop plans cover to the following topics
 Electricity basics &amp;amp; Ohm’s Law Electronics basics Circuit components What is a solder? More on soldering equipment Practice session Making your own circuit (Carry it home)  Turns out I bought the first ticket for the workshop. I had couple of failed attempts of learning to solder due to which I usually ended going to a electrical shop to get my circuits soldered.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Redesigning the fedimg AMI creation process - Part 1</title>
      <link>https://stg.words.yudocaa.in/blog/redesigning-fedimg-part-i/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Jan 2017 20:00:00 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://stg.words.yudocaa.in/blog/redesigning-fedimg-part-i/</guid>
      <description>What is fedimg? Fedimg is a Python-powered service that uploads the Fedora Cloud images on various Cloud providers. such as Amazon Web Services (AWS) .
How does it currently work? Fedimg listens to fedmsg for nightly as well as the production compose builds messages. On receiving a new message, the FedimgConsumer triggers the upload process. fedimg uses fedfind to extract the metadata for the compose from where it get&amp;rsquo;s the URL for the compressed raw image files.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Autocloud: What&#39;s new?</title>
      <link>https://stg.words.yudocaa.in/blog/autocloud-whats-new/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Aug 2016 17:28:00 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://stg.words.yudocaa.in/blog/autocloud-whats-new/</guid>
      <description>Autocloud was released during the Fedora 23 cycle as a part of the Two Week Atomic Process.
Previously, it used to listen to fedmsg for successful Koji builds. Whenever, there is a new message the AutocloudConsumer queues these message for processing. The Autocloud job service then listens to the queue, downloads the images and runs the tests using Tunir. A more detailed post about it&amp;rsquo;s release can be read here.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Receiving Weechat Notifications on mobile via Pushover</title>
      <link>https://stg.words.yudocaa.in/blog/receiving-weechat-notifications-on-mobile-via-pushover/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Apr 2016 11:44:00 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://stg.words.yudocaa.in/blog/receiving-weechat-notifications-on-mobile-via-pushover/</guid>
      <description>I recently switched to use Weechat as my primary IRC client from X-Chat. I did a setup of Weechat on my Digital Ocean box.
Weechat setup turned out to be super simple and out of the box. I am running Weechat within a tmux session. But the problem I was facing was due to poor internet connection (thanks to Airtel for this and this was my primary reason for switching to weechat from Xchat) I got disconnected from the DO box quite often.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introducing Bugyou</title>
      <link>https://stg.words.yudocaa.in/blog/introducing-bugyou/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Jan 2016 14:09:43 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://stg.words.yudocaa.in/blog/introducing-bugyou/</guid>
      <description>We developed Autocloud as a part of Fedora 23 release cycle as a part of Two week atomic image.
Autocloud publishes the messages to fedmsg when the image is queued, running, success and failed.
What is Bugyou? Bugyou files issues for failed tests from Autocloud. Bugyou is part of Fedora Project. It listens to Autocloud messages from fedmsg and files bug for images which have failed the tests. Bugyou keeps updating the status of the images in the bug and closes the issue once the tests are successful.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Migrate a running process into tmux</title>
      <link>https://stg.words.yudocaa.in/blog/migrate-a-running-process-into-tmux/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 Dec 2014 12:00:00 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://stg.words.yudocaa.in/blog/migrate-a-running-process-into-tmux/</guid>
      <description>Being a regular tmux user. Migrating a running process into tmux using reptyr comes handy.
reptyr is a utility for taking an existing running program and attaching it to a new terminal. Started a long-running process over ssh, but have to leave and don&amp;rsquo;t want to interrupt it? Just start a screen, use reptyr to grab it, and then kill the ssh session and head on home.
The package available in Fedora/Ubuntu repositories.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to get started with Open Source</title>
      <link>https://stg.words.yudocaa.in/blog/how-to-get-started-with-open-source/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Mar 2014 00:30:00 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://stg.words.yudocaa.in/blog/how-to-get-started-with-open-source/</guid>
      <description>I have been involved in Durgapur Linux User&amp;rsquo;s Group for around last five years. I have been contributing to various open source projects quite sometime. The primary reason on why I contribute to open source is the feeling, the enjoyment when you send a patch or a PR to a open source project. It makes you happy when millions of people use your few lines of code in day to day life.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Darkserver Improvement: Pen Down</title>
      <link>https://stg.words.yudocaa.in/blog/darkserver-improvement-pen-down/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Sep 2013 12:00:00 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://stg.words.yudocaa.in/blog/darkserver-improvement-pen-down/</guid>
      <description>Lot of things to do!
Lot of things to do!
Lot of things to do!
This was continuously revovlving around my head for last 2 weeks. I had to deploy the work i had done on staging instance and test it. But wait! I had never written a setup.py before, never made a RPM package before.
While in college, I had a fascination toward RPM packaging as most of my college seniors had created a RPM package sometime or other.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Darkserver Improvement: Web Dashboard</title>
      <link>https://stg.words.yudocaa.in/blog/darkserver-improvement-web-dashboard/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Sep 2013 12:00:00 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://stg.words.yudocaa.in/blog/darkserver-improvement-web-dashboard/</guid>
      <description>There has been a lot of changes since I last posted my blog.
Darkserver’s command line dashboard now supports the secondary architecture. You can easily shutdown the darkproducer of specifying which architecture to shutdown.
.. code::
dark&amp;gt; shutdown darkproducer arch  The support for multiple buildqueues was removed.
After a rigorous testing on my laptop, i pushed the code to the dev instance that was assigned to me. But, a mysterious error happened, nor the pid or the daemon of darkproducer was getting created.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Darkserver Improvement</title>
      <link>https://stg.words.yudocaa.in/blog/darkserver-improvement/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Jul 2013 12:00:00 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://stg.words.yudocaa.in/blog/darkserver-improvement/</guid>
      <description>I am currently doing some manual testing of my code, and it proved to be vital. It helped me figure out a lot of bugs. One of seemed weird to me in the beginning: The get here returned an error.
.. code::
Method Not Allowed This is an XML-RPC server. Only POST requests are accepted.  The project required a heavy amount of download, so my mentor gave me a dev instance to test out my code, all seemed to be fine, with the code properly working on local machine.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Darkserver Improvement: Week Two and Week Three</title>
      <link>https://stg.words.yudocaa.in/blog/darkserver-improvement-week-two-and-week-three/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Jul 2013 12:00:00 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://stg.words.yudocaa.in/blog/darkserver-improvement-week-two-and-week-three/</guid>
      <description>It’s been two weeks since i last posted my report on Darkserver. I could not post week two update as I had been down with bad health(seasonal changes + Loo). With the week coming to an end and /me recovering from fever, i badly hurt my right wrist and that was end of it. I somehow manage to move myself to a new city, Bengaluru. The week passed as a trauma for me :’(</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Google Summer of Code 2013: Welcome Kit</title>
      <link>https://stg.words.yudocaa.in/blog/google-summer-of-code-2013-welcome-kit/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Jun 2013 12:00:00 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://stg.words.yudocaa.in/blog/google-summer-of-code-2013-welcome-kit/</guid>
      <description>Today, I got my GSoC welcome Kit. YaY!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Darkserver Improvement: Week One</title>
      <link>https://stg.words.yudocaa.in/blog/darkserver-improvement-week-one/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Jun 2013 12:00:00 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://stg.words.yudocaa.in/blog/darkserver-improvement-week-one/</guid>
      <description>The ‘Google Summer of Code’ code period began on June 17 and it’s already one week into it. Prior to the beginning of the coding period, I went into the depths of the darkserver codebase. In the current version of Darkserver, the link present in the libimporter are hardlinks and it is pretty well visible on Github
So, I removed the urls and the values from the libimporter and made it configurable via config files.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Darkserver Improvement: Random Scribblings</title>
      <link>https://stg.words.yudocaa.in/blog/darkserver-improvement-random-scribblings/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Jun 2013 12:00:00 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://stg.words.yudocaa.in/blog/darkserver-improvement-random-scribblings/</guid>
      <description>It was worth trying to sit down with pen and paper and sketch out the compete workflow of Darkserver. I got the idea to try out this stuff from Vivek’s blogpost. Though, I could not get hold of a board but A4 did the job for me and it is really proving out to be helpful.
.. slides: ../galleries/random_scribblings.JPG ../galleries/random_scribblings2.JPG</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Darkserver Improvement: Getting Prepared</title>
      <link>https://stg.words.yudocaa.in/blog/darkserver-improvement-getting-prepared/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 22 Jun 2013 12:00:00 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://stg.words.yudocaa.in/blog/darkserver-improvement-getting-prepared/</guid>
      <description>The Google Summer of Code 2013 results was declared on 27th May 2013, in between my semester exam so i had no time to devote until the end of my semester exams and /me returning back to my home.
With the beginning of the 2nd week of June, I started to hack around with the project, Darkserver. The project is available on GitHub.
That week was pretty much a reading week rather than coding week as I had to go through all kinds of documentation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Darkserver Improvement: Google Summer of Code 2013</title>
      <link>https://stg.words.yudocaa.in/blog/darkserver-improvement-google-summer-of-code-2013/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Jun 2013 12:00:00 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://stg.words.yudocaa.in/blog/darkserver-improvement-google-summer-of-code-2013/</guid>
      <description>.. image:: ../galleries/gsoc.jpg :align: center
It’s better later than never. It’s been two week since the Google Summer of Code 2013 results were announced and I am glad to say that I got selected this year.
I will be working on Darkserver Improvement under Fedora. One can see a draft of my proposal here. My mentor is Kushal Das and i am really helpful for helping me out in the whole process both in code and application.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
